Guide to the Committee on General Education, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Committee on General Education, Yale University, records
1948-1956
RU 434
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
The records consist of correspondence, reports, and notes documenting the work of the Committee on General Education.
Yale University. Committee on General Education
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 6 (YRG 6), Records of Yale committees.
Arrangement
Arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
The committee was formed and chaired by President A. Whitney Griswold in order to study the educational program of Yale College.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, reports, and notes documenting the work of the Committee on General Education.
Universities and colleges -- Curricula; Griswold, Alfred Whitney, 1906-1963; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University. Committee on General Education; Yale University. President's Office
- Committee on General Education records, Accession 1956-A-002
  - Admissions, Statistics on, 1949-1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Advanced Subject Matter Exams, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Arts, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arts: "The Syllabus in the Arts", 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Basic and Distributional Requirements I, ways of regarding, 1953 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Basic and Distributional Requirements II, 1953 January 22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - British Schools and Colleges--Summer, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "A Report on Six Weeks in England by T. C. Mendenhall"
  - Carroll, R. C. comments, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Compromise on partial proposal, 1953 April 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Drafting Committee: report, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Engineering Curriculum, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Engineering School, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Freshman Year, 1952 December 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Freshman Year: Statistics, 1948-1952 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Graduate Schools, Deans, 1953 January 7 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Harvard's General Education; meeting with D. Owen, ? March 11 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Ideas and Hunches", undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Meeting [agenda and minutes], 1952 November 5 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Meeting [notes], 1953 February 25 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Noyes, E. S. comments, 1953 July 21 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Objections to Present System, ? March 24 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Organizational Meeting, 1952 December 29 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Plan A and Plan B, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Predicted Scores, 1952 October 8 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Press Comments on Report, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Reports and Minutes, 1945-1955 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Report of the President's Committee on General Education, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Report, Dean's Revisions, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Report, Drafts, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Report, General Introduction and Outline, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Report, Revised Introduction, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Report, J. K.'s views, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - School and College Study of General Education (Andover Committee) Interim Report, 1952 April (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Science I, Science III, Physics I, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - The Sciences meeting, 1953 February 18 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Social Sciences meeting, 1953 February 11 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Social Sciences and History, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Syllabus, 1953 January 29 and February 4 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Syllabus and Examination Plan, 1953 January 29 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Yale College, Dean, 1952 December 18 (Box 3, Folder 41)